[{"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ea", "question": "In which Star Wars movie does Darth Vader reveal that he is Luke Skywalker's father?", "answer": "The Empire Strikes Back", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c92a", "question": "What is a dromedary?", "answer": "One-humped camel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c25e", "question": "What is a wallaby?", "answer": "A kangaroo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339422", "question": "Who played the role of Jade in the 2009 movie \"The Hangover\"?", "answer": "Heather Graham", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60136faa1381754895396379", "question": "In 2000, what character was elected U.S. President in the DC universe?", "answer": "Lex Luthor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3e2", "question": "How did Buffalo Bill die?", "answer": "Kidney failure", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133920b", "question": "What early 1990's dance craze was launched by \"The Simpsons\"?", "answer": "The Bartman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cc9", "question": "What keyboard instrument with steam whistles was named for a mythological Greek muse?", "answer": "Calliope", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c016", "question": "What did American Harland David Sanders give to the world in the 1930s?", "answer": "Kentucky Fried Chicken", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c841", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the duct of Wirsung?", "answer": "The pancreas", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baf6", "question": "What sporting event is also called \"birling\"?", "answer": "Log rolling", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8aa2501dd7bf43be5e758", "question": "\"Cohen\" is Hebrew for what?", "answer": "Priest", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c59d", "question": "What word denotes the energy an object has because it is in motion?", "answer": "Kinetic", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a469", "question": "Burkino Faso is a former colony of which European country?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b1", "question": "Who played the female lead role in the 2007 movie \"Stardust\"?", "answer": "Claire Danes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015fcaefe83fe1f2a824c43", "question": "At the age of 16, Saint Patrick was kidnapped by pirates. What work did his captors force him to do?", "answer": "They made him tend and rear animals", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe655c9ae7e414034b5aeba", "question": "Persephone became trapped in the underworld after eating what?", "answer": "Pomegranate seeds", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a19c", "question": "Grace Metalious wrote which famous novel and TV show by the same name?", "answer": "Peyton Place", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067fa2ff9c0647b50a8086", "question": "What years did Nancy Reagan serve as the First of the United States?", "answer": "1981 to 1989", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea366cff048f679a45ab0d", "question": "What are the bones in the fingers called?", "answer": "Phalanges", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b89d", "question": "What do golfers call a putt that is short enough to be conceded?", "answer": "A gimme", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937e9a508d98002fdd6339b", "question": "Who is Donald Duck's girlfriend?", "answer": "Daisy Duck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe65c321f3c0ead6880d60f", "question": "What weapon dominated the Battle of Agincourt?", "answer": "Longbow", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec8517ec223966ae8f8803", "question": "Carl Gerhard Busch is the full name of which \"X-Files\" character?", "answer": "Cigarette Smoking Man", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb675c5dad637d903c883d", "question": "According to its former minister of tourism, which country is known abroad for its three Rs: reggae, romance and running?", "answer": "Jamaica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600cc6d76de0eb824d4052f9", "question": "Where is the world\u2019s largest living tree canopy, the size of three soccer fields?", "answer": "India -- A 550-year-old ficus benghalensis tree there, known as Thimmamma Marrimanu, has combined crowns that span 5.41 acres.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6aa7c20565ad31a57c819", "question": "Who is last in succession for president of the U.S.?", "answer": "Secretary of Homeland Security", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a831", "question": "The powerful Inca empire had its capital seat at Cuzco in what modern-day South American country?", "answer": "Peru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef5f566ce05a3942286e41", "question": "Who was the highest paid athlete of 2018?", "answer": "Floyd Mayweather", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b62", "question": "The author Bram Stoker was what nationality?", "answer": "Irish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a44", "question": "What author created the characters Ponyboy and Sodapop?", "answer": "S.E. Hinton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa3a8fc73aa70ea0b70adf", "question": "What is the oldest city in the world?", "answer": "Damascus (The capital of Syria has evidence of continuous habitation dating back at least 11,000 years)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b572", "question": "What is Grappa?", "answer": "An Alcoholic Drink", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e83", "question": "Who first appeared in the 1939 children's book \"Cecily G and the Nine Monkeys\"?", "answer": "Curious George", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8c5", "question": "What desert is home to the Ahaggar and Tibesti mountains?", "answer": "Sahara", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59da1bfaf6756c9b30ba14ff", "question": "Who was the star of the TV cooking show \"The Galloping Gourmet\"?", "answer": "Graham Kerr", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc3b", "question": "What plant is used to make tequila?", "answer": "Blue agave", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339917", "question": "What daytime soap opera takes place in the fictional town of Salem?", "answer": "Days of Our Lives", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f17", "question": "What author created Gormenghast?", "answer": "Mervyn Peake", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c08d", "question": "Which heroine comes from Amphipolis?", "answer": "Xena", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c00c", "question": "In the tech field, what does AMD stand for?", "answer": "Advanced Micro Devices", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1a6", "question": "In what country was the last original Volkswagen Beetle produced, in July 2003?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c87e", "question": "What dinosaur contemporary has a name meaning \"ancient feather\"?", "answer": "Archaeopteryx", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d35", "question": "What English town was William Shakespeare born in?", "answer": "Stratford-upon-Avon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a50b", "question": "Lombard Street in London is the equivalent to which famous street in the US?", "answer": "Wall Street", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391f0", "question": "HBO's TV show \"True Blood\" is based on a book series by whom?", "answer": "Charlene Harris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab42", "question": "What is the capital of Austria?", "answer": "Vienna", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a822", "question": "When facing Mount Rushmore, which president's head is farthest to your left?", "answer": "George Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ba7", "question": "What museum, designed by Frank Lloyd Wright, was opened in 1959?", "answer": "Guggenheim Museum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ecae392790ded87bb38fd8a", "question": "According to flight logs how may times did Bill Clinton travel on Jeffrey Epstein's \"Lolita Express\" aircraft? ", "answer": "27", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff25c3231a458464a93c47d", "question": "What kind of food is Avgolemono?", "answer": "A mixture of egg yolk, lemon juice and broth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff515beff04d658268c92ec", "question": "What queen led a famous revolt against the Roman Empire?", "answer": "Zenobia, queen of the Palmyrene Empire, expanded the empire, by conquering Egypt and expelling the Roman prefect, Tenagino Probus.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5e9", "question": "What color is a Northern Cardinal?", "answer": "Red", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c87", "question": "Who has the only speaking part in Mel Brooks' \"Silent Movie\"?", "answer": "Marcel Marceau", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bf1", "question": "In which city's harbor would you find the statue of The Little Mermaid?", "answer": "Copenhagen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba85", "question": "Who succeeded Tom Brokaw as anchor on NBC\u2019s Nightly News in 2004?", "answer": "Brian Williams", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec8a94ec223966ae8f8832", "question": "What is the setting for the film \"It's a Wonderful Life\"?", "answer": "Bedford Falls, New York", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9a8", "question": "What theme part was opened in 2001 next to Disneyland?", "answer": "Disney's California Adventure", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e96efe83fe1f2a824be6", "question": "Where was the first UN summit on the environment, air pollution and global warming held, in 1992?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c8f2fbde8045e48466e4", "question": "Which farm animal is known as a ram, ewe, and lamb?", "answer": "Sheep -- Female sheep are called ewes, male sheep are called rams, and baby sheep are called lambs.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba1f", "question": "In golf, what is the traditional name for a number 3 wood?", "answer": "Spoon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338df5", "question": "What Broadway team collaborated on \"Flora the Red Menace\" before writing \"Cabaret\" and \"Chicago\"?", "answer": "John Kander and Fred Ebb", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fc2f837cee580c7f8fd1e60", "question": "What is the tallest mountain in the contiguous US?", "answer": "Mount Whitney", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397ad", "question": "What former Cosby Show star tied the knot with Lenny Kravitz in 1987?", "answer": "Lisa Bonet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a80f", "question": "What is the capital of the Canadian province of Saskatchewan?", "answer": "Regina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5902a012cad1ec93f27df767", "question": "What are the four primary ingredients of a traditional Irish coffee?", "answer": "Irish whisky, coffee, sugar and cream", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600cc9176de0eb824d405301", "question": "Where is the New York City Marathon start line?", "answer": "Staten Island -- It starts at the base of the Verrazano-Narrows Bridge in Staten Island and ends in Central Park.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a136", "question": "What film starred Helen Hunt, Cary Elwes and Bill Paxton?", "answer": "Twister", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5ba", "question": "What does a phobophobe fear?", "answer": "Fear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe69ccc20565ad31a57c76f", "question": "Who was the captain of the \"Mayflower\"?", "answer": "Christopher Jones", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b466", "question": "What year did General Sherman order Atlanta be burned?", "answer": "1864", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393c0", "question": "What Al Pacino movie portrayed a bank robbery on August 22, 1972?", "answer": "Dog Day Afternoon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b07c", "question": "What WWII general was known as \"Old Blood and Guts\"?", "answer": "Patton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397b9", "question": "What instrument did Don Henley play as a member of Eagles?", "answer": "Drums", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3acfc73aa70ea0b70ae1", "question": "What is the highest waterfall in Europe?", "answer": "The\u00a0Krimml Waterfalls", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b63a", "question": "Which company was the first to offer a Valentine's Day chocolate box?", "answer": "Cadbury", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0fa", "question": "What two timezones are unique to Canada and not shared with the US?", "answer": "Atlantic Standard Time and Newfoundland Standard Time", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6a4", "question": "What fruit is grown extensively on Cape Cod?", "answer": "Cranberries", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b713", "question": "According to tradition, what must be saved from the yule log?", "answer": "A piece of wood to light next year's yule log", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2b6", "question": "Which of Henry VIII's wives was the mother of Queen Elizabeth I?", "answer": "Anne Boleyn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59a1a36012f2a7826b9b8725", "question": "Alba is the Gaelic name for what country?", "answer": "Scotland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c56d", "question": "In what decade did scientists first split the atom?", "answer": "1930s", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be51", "question": "What Major League Soccer team signed David Beckham to a $50 million contract in 2007?", "answer": "The Los Angeles Galaxy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b0e86c964118b2bb3809c5", "question": "In Slovenia, Saint Valentine is considered the saint of good health and the patron of whom?", "answer": "Beekeepers and pilgrims", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cfd", "question": "In which movie did Veronica Lake portray a witch?", "answer": "I Married a Witch", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be70", "question": "What is Michigan Stadium also known as?", "answer": "The Big House", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7ca04877e98cb97778a00", "question": "What is the capital of the British Virgin Islands?", "answer": "Road Town", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cfa", "question": "What was the name of King Arthur's sword?", "answer": "Excalibur", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8aa0201dd7bf43be5e755", "question": "What goes up and down but remains in the same place?", "answer": "Stairs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c536", "question": "What planet is tilted on its axis more than any other?", "answer": "Uranus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5902a066cad1ec93f27df76a", "question": "Which Bohemian city gave us the Pilsner?", "answer": "Pilsen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5af25d55b63e5727cf5a4864", "question": "\"Stay\" was a hit single for which UK band in 1992?", "answer": "Shakespeares Sister", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e6bcfe83fe1f2a824bd1", "question": "Who gave Queen Elizabeth I the soubriquet \"Gloriana\"?", "answer": "Edmund Spenser, in his epic poem \"The Faerie Queene\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd9712723c87fd04dd15e4a", "question": "Who is often credited with inventing the thermometer?", "answer": "Galileo Galilei", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f0d", "question": "What author created the character of Adam Dalgliesh?", "answer": "P. D. James", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c420", "question": "How many moons does Mars have?", "answer": "Two", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133911b", "question": "What year did H. G. Wells publish the novel \"The Time Machine\"?", "answer": "1895", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8fa", "question": "What redbrick complex lies between the Alexander Garden and Red Square?", "answer": "The Kremlin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b070", "question": "Who the first American World Chess Champion?", "answer": "Bobby Fisher", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ad", "question": "Which female gymnast won 3 golds and a silver at the 1972 Summer Olympics?", "answer": "Olga Korbut", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a6c", "question": "What was the name of the 80\u2019s band formed by Roland Orzabal and Curt Smith?", "answer": "Tears for Fears", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133befd", "question": "How many players are there on a standard soccer team on field?", "answer": "11", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a54f", "question": "Which US state is home to the Klamath Mountains?", "answer": "Oregon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ec23f08dc25ca9e12ef634", "question": "In \"Gulliver's Travels\", what is the name of the flying island?", "answer": "Laputa", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ab5", "question": "Who wrote, Papa's Angels: A Christmas Story in 1996?", "answer": "Collin Wilcox Paxton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015e024fe83fe1f2a824b87", "question": "Who organized the famous \"March of the Mill Children\" from Philadelphia to President Theodore Roosevelt's summer home in 1903?", "answer": "Mary Harris Jones", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59029db7cad1ec93f27df751", "question": "What popular French apple brandy is made by distilling cider made from selected apples?", "answer": "Calvados", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb93", "question": "Which commemorative US state quarter depicts salmon leaping in front of a mountain on its reverse side?", "answer": "Washington", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c467", "question": "What is the proper term for a young eel?", "answer": "An elver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ab96fc86faa38a764be525", "question": "What car did Kowalski commit to delivering in the 1971 film \"Vanishing Point\"?", "answer": "Dodge Challenger (1970 Dodge Challenger R/T 440 Magnum, to be specific)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b898", "question": "What four colors traditionally correspond with first through fourth place ribbons?", "answer": "Blue, Red, White, Yellow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a35a", "question": "What is the most sacred river of India?", "answer": "The Ganges", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c77cf2f24f0f7a362efd54c", "question": "How many claws in total does the average adult cat have?", "answer": "18", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b225", "question": "In which city was American actor Bob Crane murdered?", "answer": "Scottsdale, Arizona", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a26d", "question": "McLean Stevenson played which character in the TV series \"M*A*S*H\"?", "answer": "Lt. Colonel Henry Blake", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f95", "question": "What rock band brought suit in 1994 claiming that Ticketmaster was an illegal monopoly?", "answer": "Pearl Jam", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8aebf01dd7bf43be5e782", "question": "How many animals are represented in the Chinese Zodiac?", "answer": "12", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c14", "question": "According to Exodus, what is the sixth plague of Egypt?", "answer": "Boils", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb1b", "question": "In what year did the Chicago Black Hawks win their first Stanley Cup?", "answer": "1934", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133916b", "question": "Who directed the movie \"Close Encounters of the Third Kind\"?", "answer": "Steven Spielberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6a7796c0f9723ab15cb5f", "question": "How many US dollars are a pound of dimes and a pound of quarters each worth?", "answer": "$20 each", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab148dbaab681b09292175", "question": "The Benz Patent-Motorwagen, widely regarded as the world\u2019s first automobile, was first built in what year?", "answer": "1885", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be98", "question": "What does \"PT\" stand for in the names of Navy PT boats?", "answer": "Patrol Torpedo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea39f9ff048f679a45ab29", "question": "What element is named after the Greek word for green?", "answer": "Chlorine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd66c07a5bfecdd737e088d", "question": "Which country made it illegal to own only one guinea pig in 2008?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d1180d4fea7fe947a22280", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for lead?", "answer": "Pb", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399e4", "question": "What actor played Ross and Monica\u2019s father, Jack, on the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Elliot Gould", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca82", "question": "What type of fat was margarine first made from in the U.S.?", "answer": "Beef", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a82a", "question": "What is the largest country in Africa in terms of land size?", "answer": "Algeria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1e4", "question": "In what country was the \"Michelin Guide\" first published in 1900?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c17", "question": "According to Exodus, what is the third plague of Egypt?", "answer": "Lice", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a647", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Colorado?", "answer": "Denver", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4a8", "question": "\"Sphenopalatine Ganglioneuralgia\" is commonly referred to as?", "answer": "Brain freeze", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff51b04ff04d658268c930b", "question": "What kind of man-eating monster did Odysseus blind?", "answer": "Cyclops", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cad7", "question": "Hydrargyrum is an old name for which element on the periodic table?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60136fc4138175489539637c", "question": "What item gives the Green Lantern his power?", "answer": "Ring -- Turns out the key to being one of the most powerful superheroes in the DC universe is the ability to accessorize.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ad", "question": "Who played the teenage prostitute in the 1976 film \"Taxi Driver\"?", "answer": "Jodie Foster", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b812", "question": "What is the nickname of Alcatraz Prison?", "answer": "The Rock", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b40", "question": "How many episodes of \"The Bob Newhart Show\" were made?", "answer": "142", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca6c", "question": "Who is generally regarded as the inventor of the internal combustion automobile?", "answer": "Karl Benz", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae53", "question": "What was the name given to the first German democracy established in 1919?", "answer": "Weimar Republic", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339889", "question": "What 1987 Michael Caine film has a zero rating on the website Rotten Tomatoes?", "answer": "Jaws 4 - The Revenge", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b67f", "question": "Who was the first American president to appear on the cover of \"People\" magazine?", "answer": "Gerald Ford", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8a4", "question": "What Pacific island chain is named for Philip IV's Austrian queen?", "answer": "The Marianas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbf2", "question": "Who created the game Space Invaders?", "answer": "Tomohiro Nishikado", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb60d05dad637d903c882c", "question": "The Rungnado 1st of May Stadium, built in honor of the May Day holiday, exists in which country?", "answer": "North Korea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a99", "question": "What other animal cartoon character made his screen debut as Porky Pig's nemesis in the 1937 short \"Porky's Duck Hunt\"?", "answer": "Daffy Duck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f8d", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"Goodbye, Mr. Chips\"?", "answer": "Greer Garson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae97", "question": "To what tribe did Sitting Bull belong?", "answer": "Sioux", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba7f", "question": "In 1995, who became the first Asian player to be named Rookie of the Year in Major League Baseball?", "answer": "Hideo Nomo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5aab2ef258d116dab4aecb44", "question": "What is dendrochronology?", "answer": "Tree ring dating", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5be57cc15415ba52ed6f0aa4", "question": "Who is the boss on NBC's TV Show \"The Office\"?", "answer": "Michael Scott", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1da", "question": "What organization in the US was co-founded by Ballington Booth?", "answer": "Volunteers of America", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd6652da5bfecdd737e085c", "question": "What was the U.S. population in 1900?", "answer": "76,094,000", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b323229bf195a31e15d738d", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Daniel Deronda\"?", "answer": "George Eliot", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9087f01dd7bf43be5e884", "question": "What is the most prominent crater on the Moon?", "answer": "Tycho", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597cd4d5e347d002c297e4b2", "question": "Born in 1962, who in the world of music has the real name Stanley Kirk Burrell?", "answer": "MC Hammer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133892d", "question": "In which comic book series did Galactus first appear?", "answer": "The Fantastic Four", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c039", "question": "Soteriophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Dependence on others", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c60e", "question": "What does a herpetologist study?", "answer": "Reptiles and amphibians", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c19a877e98cb97778978", "question": "Which French landmark is known for its red windmill?", "answer": "Moulin Rouge", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5afad9cf430e050a5df0d115", "question": "Who were the first people in the world to eat popcorn?", "answer": "The Natives in the Americas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1f1", "question": "Who played the lead female in the 1956 film \"Meet Me in Las Vegas\"?", "answer": "Cyd Charisse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394fc", "question": "In the TV series \"Doctor Who\", what does the acronym TARDIS stand for?", "answer": "Time and Relative Dimension in Space", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b61d", "question": "What type of salad was invented by the owner of the Hollywood eatery the Brown Derby?", "answer": "The Cobb Salad", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c31d", "question": "What is added to bread to make it swell?", "answer": "Yeast", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe9f6dcff048f679a45aadf", "question": "What is Johannes Kepler best known for?", "answer": "Kepler's laws of planetary motion", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b87e", "question": "What four notes are represented on the four strings of a ukulele?", "answer": "G, C, E, A", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393f5", "question": "What actor played the role of Jean-Baptiste Emanuel Zorg in the 1997 movie \"The Fifth Element\"?", "answer": "Gary Oldman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391e4", "question": "Whose memory is the movie \"Gladiator\" dedicated to?", "answer": "Oliver Reed's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0ee", "question": "Who was the first African-American to be appointed as a US Supreme Court justice?", "answer": "Thurgood Marshall", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a92d", "question": "Where is the Swimming Hall of Fame located?", "answer": "Fort Lauderdale, Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4da", "question": "Which is larger, a baseball or a softball?", "answer": "A softball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5990f467fa5fdd6dd25324e0", "question": "Which band sang \"Mull of Kintyre\"?", "answer": "Wings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59774295284458f1d7854421", "question": "What contestant-based reality television series aired in the United States originated in Holland?", "answer": "The Voice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2fd", "question": "On the sitcom \"Happy Days\", the character of Matsuo Takahashi was better known by what name?", "answer": "Arnold", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c71a", "question": "What planet's four largest moons are collectively known as the Galilean Moons?", "answer": "Jupiter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab0e", "question": "Athens is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60062b98c9d816e292245c20", "question": "Where is the first underwater art museum in the U.S.?", "answer": "Santa Rosa Beach, Florida", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5990af23b72eedf883a8c704", "question": "What is Chopin's \"Piano Sonata in B flat minor\" also known as?", "answer": "The Funeral March", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389b8", "question": "What musical instrument does Sherlock Holmes play for relaxation?", "answer": "Violin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8b6a901dd7bf43be5e7e0", "question": "Who coined the phrase \"slam dunk\"?", "answer": "Chick Hearn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339996", "question": "For what 2005 film did George Clooney win a Best Supporting Actor Oscar?", "answer": "Syriana", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c75f", "question": "In what year did the Soviet Union launch its first Sputnik satellite?", "answer": "1957", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b542", "question": "What was the official language of England for over 600 years?", "answer": "French", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfed", "question": "Who was America's first billionaire?", "answer": "John D. Rockefeller", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a090", "question": "What was John Wayne's real name?", "answer": "Marion Morrison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b19a", "question": "What was the name of the official 1972 Summer Olympics logo?", "answer": "Bright Sun", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8a5", "question": "What name is shared by the rivers that run through Denison, Texas and Hanoi, Vietnam?", "answer": "Red River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921c", "question": "What city did the band U2 form in?", "answer": "Dublin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb5cbd5dad637d903c881f", "question": "What is the official State fruit of New York?", "answer": "Apple", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c62", "question": "Who directed \"Star Wars: Episode VI - Return of the Jedi\"?", "answer": "Richard Marquand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fe2", "question": "According to the TV series, how many stories are there in \"The Naked City\"?", "answer": "Eight million", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a782", "question": "What line of Latitude lies at 23 degrees and 27 minutes north of the equator?", "answer": "Tropic of Cancer", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe9f12bff048f679a45aaaf", "question": "What are baby owls called?", "answer": "Owlets or nestlings", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b08c", "question": "What was the nickname of American frontiersman Christopher Houston Carson?", "answer": "Kit", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339844", "question": "What three actresses were the original Charlie's Angels?", "answer": "Farrah Fawcett, Kate Jackson and Jaclyn Smith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4fd", "question": "What was the name of the Apollo 11 lunar module?", "answer": "Eagle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aed1", "question": "Which US state was the first to secede from the Union in 1860?", "answer": "South Carolina", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aed4", "question": "When did Alaska become a US state?", "answer": "1959", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a262", "question": "What is the name of the summer camp in the \"Friday the 13th\" movie series?", "answer": "Camp Crystal Lake\u00a0", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60160146fe83fe1f2a824c5d", "question": "Which famous scientist stuck out his tongue in a now-iconic photo?", "answer": "Albert Einstein stuck out his tongue after he grew tired of the various poses requested by photographer Arthur Sasse.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4c4", "question": "When did Indira Gandhi's first term as Prime Minister of India begin?", "answer": "1966", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6012197663c99d48cd169af9", "question": "What is it called when a bottle of champagne is open with a sword?", "answer": "Sabering", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59f9ba61364247bf200fb897", "question": "Which duo recorded the 1981 song \"Endless Love\"?", "answer": "Lionel Ritchie and Diana Ross", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338944", "question": "In Greek mythology, what is the name of the staff carried by Hermes?", "answer": "The Caduceus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c124877e98cb97778973", "question": "Which US state is \"Almost Heaven\"?", "answer": "West Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "590681c6ff9c0647b50a8097", "question": "Under what name did Nintendo re-release the Nintendo Entertainment System in 2016?", "answer": "Nintendo Entertainment System: NES Classic Edition", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b91e", "question": "What is the body of water that surrounds a castle called?", "answer": "A moat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5901db26709c1c34536e6eb1", "question": "In what sport would a contestant perform a \"Fosberry Flop\"?", "answer": "High jump", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b3724d1c3f17ccc40c8e23", "question": "What English party was politician Arthur Hayday associated with?", "answer": "Labour Party", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d1195b4fea7fe947a2228e", "question": "What is in the Red Data List?", "answer": "Threatened Species", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea788fff048f679a45abdb", "question": "What is a \"Haricot Vert\"?", "answer": "A tender string bean", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfcd", "question": "In bowling what is the term for knocking down all pins with 2 consecutive balls?", "answer": "A Spare\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b49", "question": "Who played Al Borland on the TV show \"Home Improvement\"?", "answer": "Richard Karn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133935c", "question": "In what city did the TV show \"Full House\" take place?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921a", "question": "What female singer is discussed at the start of the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Madonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f85", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for the first screen appearance of Mary Poppins?", "answer": "Julie Andrews", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "591c37dc815febcc896f9275", "question": "What is the fourth sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Cancer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe522ae1bf59ab7d2e380e9", "question": "\"100% Squeezed Sunshine\" has been which company's ad slogan?", "answer": "Tropicana", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f95a97e55722f97b22684d0", "question": "What short film featured Mickey Mouse\u2019s first appearance?", "answer": "Plane Crazy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be88", "question": "What type of a tree killed Jim Croce?", "answer": "Pecan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c42", "question": "What clarinetist was nicknamed the \"King of Swing\"?", "answer": "Benny Goodman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb4d", "question": "In what year were Skittles candy first sold in the US?", "answer": "1974", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4c3", "question": "Who succeeded Indira Gandhi as Prime Minister of India following her assassination in 1984?", "answer": "Rajiv Gandhi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a7dc20565ad31a57c7f0", "question": "What was the first slogan for OREO cookies?", "answer": "Oh! Oh! Oreo!", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339418", "question": "What actor provided the voice for the song \"Thriller\"?", "answer": "Vincent Price", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339651", "question": "What kind of animal is the title character in the 1998 movie \"Paulie\"?", "answer": "Parrot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b323244bf195a31e15d738e", "question": "What year did George Eliot publish her novel \"Daniel Deronda\"?", "answer": "1876", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abca", "question": "South Africa has water access to which ocean?", "answer": "Indian and Atlantic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf22", "question": "The use of astronomical phenomena to predict earthly and human events is called what?", "answer": "Astrology", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b6c", "question": "What Hanna-Barbera cartoon character was known for the catchphrase \"Exit, Stage Left\" when dashing off?", "answer": "Snagglepuss", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015f0fbfe83fe1f2a824c14", "question": "Which world-changing invention was patented in the US on Valentine's Day, 1876?", "answer": "Telephone", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a42a", "question": "In what country would you see \"whirling dervishes\"?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe3eb1b38e4e5d4832e6319", "question": "Which country's subway system was paralyzed by a deadly nerve gas attack in 1995?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339723", "question": "Bruce Springsteen was given what nickname?", "answer": "The Boss", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ab0", "question": "During the 1960's, what musician formed and fronted the band \"The Mothers of Invention\"?", "answer": "Frank Zappa", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd18b6a29d03ab85b632b31", "question": "Who said, \"If you can't explain it to a six year old, you don't understand it yourself\"?", "answer": "Einstein", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab19", "question": "What country is the Arch of Hardian located in?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396b0", "question": "What Oscar-winning Best Picture is named for a type of rose?", "answer": "American Beauty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b36d", "question": "Which country was the first to allow women to vote in 1893?\u00a0", "answer": "New Zealand\u00a0", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6559aae7e414034b5aeb5", "question": "Which Norse god\u2019s image is Santa Claus partially based on?", "answer": "Odin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afd8", "question": "Who was shot by Jack Ruby?", "answer": "Lee Harvey Oswald", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e8a8a26404ad935a7e1a642", "question": "In what country was Shakira born?", "answer": "Colombia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c05", "question": "What is Dorothy's last name in \"The Wonderful Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "Gale", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5feb34897e83c707845b20cb", "question": "The \"Eddie Murphy Rule\" banned certain kinds of insider trading in commodities markets. It was inspired by Murphy\u2019s role in what film?", "answer": "Trading Places", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339798", "question": "Who did Michael Jackson marry in May 1994?", "answer": "Lisa Marie Pressley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eea", "question": "Drug lord Mr. Big is the villain of what James Bond novel?", "answer": "Live and Let Die", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a95120565ad31a57c801", "question": "Xerxes the Great was the king of what empire?", "answer": "Achaemenid Empire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f16abaf7c52aae91cc07e0", "question": "What is Australia's highest mainland mountain?", "answer": "Mount Kosciuszko", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b778", "question": "The traditional chef's hat has 100 pleats, which symbolizes the number of what?", "answer": "Ways to cook an egg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909d261bb53d1af65886508", "question": "Candy canes are said to have originated from which European country?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a4b", "question": "What celebrity showed up for a court appearance in 2005 wearing pajama bottoms?", "answer": "Michael Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d115b04fea7fe947a22269", "question": "What year did The Gambia gain its independence from the United Kingdom?", "answer": "1965", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdf0", "question": "What fitness program did Judi Sheppard Missett create in 1969?", "answer": "Jazzercise", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa5707c73aa70ea0b70b2f", "question": "Which U.S. town is home to the world's largest rose bush?", "answer": "Tombstone, Arizona", "category": "geography"}]